Margarita Cano
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Margarita Cano papers
1982-1985
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Margarita Cano
0.2 linear feet
Margarita Cano's papers measure 0.2 linear feet and date from 1983-1985. The collection primarily concerns the 1983 exhibition The Miami Generation, 9 Cuban-American Artists, an exhibition organized by The Cuban Museum of Art in Culture in cooperation with the Miami-Dade Public Library System and for which Cano served as Project Director. Curated by Guilio V. Blanc, the exhibition included work by Mario Bencomo, Maria Brito-Avellana, Humberto Calzada, Pablo Cano, Emilio Falero, Fernando Garcia, Juan Gonzalez, Carlos Macia, and Cesar Trasobares. The exhibition traveled to Meridian House International in Washington, DC and later to Philadelphia at the Balch Institute for Ethnic Studies in 1985. Found are two files of correspondence, exhibition planning and publicity files, a catalog, checklist, and photocopied news clippings. Most of the documents are photocopies. There is also one folder of slides and photographs of works of art in the exhibition.
Biographical Note
Born in 1932 in Havana, Cuba, Margarita Cano began her studies at the University of Havana. She left Cuba in 1962 to settle in Miami and later became director of arts for the Miami-Dade County Public Library. The arts programs she initiated focused on the work of African-American and Cuban-American artists and eventually led to the establishment of a permanent collection at the library. An artist herself, Cano's artwork focuses on Cuban scenes painted on wood in a miniature style. In 1983 she served as project director for the exhibition The Miami Generation: Nine Cuban-American Artists (La Generacion de Miami: Nueve Artistas Cubano Americanos), curated by Latin American curator and scholar, Guilio Blanc.
Scope and Content Note
Margarita Cano's papers measure 0.2 linear feet and date from 1983-1985. The collection primarily concerns the 1983 exhibition The Miami Generation, 9 Cuban-American Artists; an exhibition organized by The Cuban Museum of Art in Culture in cooperation with the Miami-Dade Public Library System for which Cano served as Project Director. Curated by Guilio V. Blanc, the exhibition included work by Mario Bencomo, Maria Brito-Avellana, Humberto Calzada, Pablo Cano, Emilio Falero, Fernando Garcia, Juan Gonzalez, Carlos Macia, and Cesar Trasobares. The exhibition traveled to Meridian House International in Washington, DC and, later, to Philadelphia at the Balch Institute for Ethnic Studies in 1985. Found are two files of correspondence, exhibition planning and publicity files, a catalog, checklist, and photocopied news clippings. Most of the documents are photocopies. There is also one folder of slides and photographs of works of art in the exhibition.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into one series:
Series 1: Exhibition Files, 1983-1985 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture (Miami, Fla.); Miami-Dade Public Library
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Cuban -- Florida -- Miami -- Exhibitions; Expatriate artists -- Florida -- Miami; Cuban American artists -- Exhibitions; Artists -- Cuba; Cuban American art -- Florida -- Miami -- Exhibitions; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- Florida -- Miami -- Exhibitions
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Slides (photographs)
Provenance
Margarita Cano donated her papers in 1997 to the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.
Restrictions on Access
Use requires an appointment.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Exhibition Files, 1983-1985, Series 1:; (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
  - Photocopied Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Photcopied Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Planning Notes, Budget, Insurance, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Photocopies of Design and Installation Sketches and Photographs, 1983 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Photocopy of a Typescript of Catalog Essay by Cynthia Jaffee McCabe, circa 1984 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Catalog, Checklist, and Invitations for Philadelphia and Washington, D.C. Venue, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Press Releases and Announcements, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Photocopies of News Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (pam))
  - Photographs and Slides of Works of Art, undated (Box 1 (pam))